Cleveland Park Garden Club 038
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Cleveland Park Garden Club Collection
1953-1984
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Cleveland Park Garden Club
038
0.7 Linear feet
2 Boxes
Arrangement
Processed without series.
Biographical / Historical
In order to promote environmental conservation and horticultural interest, area residents founded the Cleveland Park Garden Club in 1953. Topics at the monthly meetings ranged from garden maintenance to community beautification projects. Slide and lecture presentations as well as garden tours were held throughout the year. The club was also active in local volunteer and civic efforts including the maintenance of the National Cathedral grounds, the safeguarding of "green spaces" in the District, and the Cleveland Park Branch Library Landscaping and Beautification project. The group also protested the District's use of DDT as a pesticide. Although the club was advertised as a community organization open to all, membership was primarily women. When the club disbanded in June 1984, the decline in membership was attributed not only to District families' exodus to the suburbs, but also to women working outside the home.
Custodial History
Philip J. Stone donated the records of the Cleveland Park Garden Club.
Scope and Contents
Records from the Cleveland Park Garden Club extend from 1953 through 1984. The collection contains correspondence, financial materials, meeting minutes, by-laws, membership lists, and newsletters. Significant items in the collection are a letter signed by First Lady Claudia Alta "Lady Bird" Johnson and the Garden Club scrapbook highlighting various projects undertaken by the group. Included are articles from the Washington Post and photographs of members and club projects.
Neighborhoods; Horticulture; Societies and clubs; Organizational Records; Correspondence; Community organization; Cleveland Park (Washington, D.C.)
- Series 1
  - Annual Program Announcements, 1973-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Report of the Secretary, 1976-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Audit Reports, 1974-1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cleveland Park Branch Library Beautification Project, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cleveland Park Branch Library Landscaping Project, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cleveland Park Branch Library Landscaping Project, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Constitution and By-laws, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dissolution Papers, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1975-1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Financial Reports, 1975-1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Flyer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ledger Book, 1960-1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Membership List, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Membership List, 1974-1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minutes and other Materials, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Minutes and other materials, 1975-1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook, 1954-1961 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Scrapbook, 1954-1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)